

# Shiva Prasad Gurram

Software Engineer

I am an Experienced Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience on Java Backend development and AWS cloud in telecommunications industry. Strong Knowledge on Application Development using Software Development Life Cycle - SDLC using Agile/Scrum methodology.

gurramshiva05@gmail.com

Hyderabad, India

in in.linkedin.com/in/shiva-prasad-gurram-2668b3129

github.com/ShivaPrasadGurram

+91 8686220206 & +91 8639565395

shivaprasadgurram.github.io/

quora.com/profile/Shiva-Prasad-Gurram

stackoverflow.com/users/11654174/shiva

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd

12/2020 - Present

Hyderabad, India

Responsibilities

- Working as a part of the scrum team.
- Strong experience in analysis, design, development, documentation, implementing and testing of software systems in Java and AWS.
- Implemented individual Microservices from existing monolithic application using Spring Boot and REST API's.
- Worked on publishing data into AWS S3 using SDK and enabled cross-region replication to copy data to another region automatically.
- Experience in using build/deploy tools such as Jenkins, Kubernetes for Continuous Integration & Deployment for Microservices.
- Hands on experience with build and deployment tools including Ant / Maven, logging and Debugging using Slf4 and Log4j.

# **Associate Software Engineer** Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd

02/2019 - 11/2020

Responsibilities:

- Worked as a part of the Scrum Team.
- Implemented REST API's from scratch.
- Worked on enhancements of enterprise application using Java and Spring boot framework.
- Wrote lambda functions to stop/start ec2 services, call API gateway, creating EBS snapshots, etc.
- Strong knowledge in AWS IAM to manage AWS services and resources and added security group inbound rules dynamically using shell scripting.
- Hands on experience on launching EC2 Instances, trouble shooting connectivity issues, AWS CLI and AWS core services

### **SKILLS**



## PERSONAL PROJECTS

Mccpro.in (09/2019 - 03/2020) ☑

- It is an e-commerce website which sells ayurveda ayush products within india.
- Consists of both Admin and User Modules.
- Integrated with mail system as well.
- Integrated with Paytm payment gateway.

MyCloudTrip.in (11/2020 - Present) ✓

 It is all about sharing the cloud knowledge to techie people in a practical way by solving real time business use cases.

Aurobindo college of Pharmaceutical Sciences (05/2018 - 06/2018)

This is a college website where it deals with college information.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS & CLOUD CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Medaram Jathara -2016

Presented MEDARAM JATHARA-2016 Android Application to the Telangana state Deputy C.M MR.KADIYAM SRIHARI GAARU and which was covered on media also on 01-28-2016.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -Associate (06/2020 - 06/2023)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) (11/2020 - 11/2022)

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2019 Architect Associate -1Z0-1072 (04/2020 - 10/2021)

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2020 Associate - 1Z0-1085-20-F (04/2020 - 10/2021)

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Technology Kakatiya Institute of Technology & Science

08/2015 - 05/2018 CGPA: 7.47

Courses

 Computer Science & Engineering

#### **INTERESTS**

Cricket

Music

Blogging